Centuries ago one man was chosen to protect all that is good. But an enemy from
the past has traveled through time to challenge him in the present.
Highlander III: The Sorcerer is a fantasy, action,
adventure film directed by Andrew Morahan.
Starts off in the 15th century, with Connor McLeod training with
another immortal swordsman, the Japanese sorcerer Nakano.
When an evil immortal named Kane kills the old wizard, the
resulting battle leaves him buried in an underground cave.
When Kane resurfaces in the 20th century to create
havoc, it's up to McLeod to stop him.
Connor 'The Highlander' MacLeod, played by Christopher Lambert.
Kane, played by Mario Van Peebles.
Alex Johnson / Sarah, played by Deborah Kara Unger.
Nakano, played by Mako.
Lt. John Stenn, played by Martin Neufeld.
Takamura, played by Daniel Dõ.
Highlander III: The Sorcerer (also known as Highlander: The Final Dimension or Highlander: The Final Conflict) is a 1994
British-Canadian-French action-adventure fantasy film and the third installment in the Highlander film series.
Set as an alternate sequel to the original film (i.e., it completely ignores and frequently contradicts the events of
Highlander II: The Quickening), it is the final Highlander film to focus on Connor MacLeod as the protagonist.
In the film, Connor MacLeod is forced to face a new, dangerous enemy, a powerful sorcerer known as Kane who
threatens to win the fabled "Prize" in order to gain world domination by eliminating MacLeod.
It grossed $36.7 million worldwide, becoming the highest grossing film in the
franchise, as well as the only one to recover its budget at the box office.
It received mostly negative reviews from critics, although it
was considered better than the previous film.
The film explores themes of new york city, martial
arts, japan, magic, immortality.
The tone is dark.